Register of the Joseph Hansen Papers, 1887-1980.
Hoover Institution Archives
- SPEECHES AND WRITINGS, 1928-1978.
  - Notes on trip to Mexico and Cuba for Organizacion Latinoamericana de Solidaridad conference, 1967 July-August (Folder 6)
  - Article on demonstration in Havana against racism in the United States, 1967 August. Holograph and typescript (Folder 7)
  - Interview in Havana by Cuban press, 1967 August. Typed transcript (Folder 8)
  - Notes on trip to Cuba and Europe, 1967 August (Folder 9)
  - Notes on trip to Europe, 1967 August-September (Folder 10)
  - "Unequivocal Situation among British Red Guards," 1967 September. Typescript (Folder 11)
  - Report to SWP Political Committee on trip to Cuba and Europe, 1967 September 14. Outline notes (Folder 12)
  - International report, SWP national convention, 1967 October 28. Typescript. Includes notes on convention (Folder 13)
  - Report on Organizacion Latinoamericana de Solidaridad conference, 1967 November 11. Notes and typescript (Folder 14)
  - Report on Cuba, SWP New York City branch, 1967 December 28. Notes (Folder 15)
  - Biographical notes for Italian edition of Leon Trotsky, In Defense of Marxism, 1968. Typescripts (Folder 16)
  - "Draft Resolution on Latin America," 1968. Outline notes (Folder 17)
  - "The Militant, " 1968
    - Notes (Folder 18)
    - Typescripts and galleys (Folder 19)
  - Notes on Fourth International European sections, 1968 (Folder 20)
  - Notes on Fourth International meeting, 1968 (Folder 21)
  - Notes on renaming World Outlook, 1968 (Folder 22)
  - "Reply by OCI" (re Organisation Communiste Internationaliste [France]), ca. 1968. Outline notes (Folder 23)
  - "Reply of the Central Committee of the SLL to the Declaration of the OCI," ca. 1968. Outline notes (Folder 24)
  - Eulogy for Rose Karsner, 1968 March 24. Typescript (Folder 25)
  - "Intellectuals and the Party," 1968 April. Outline notes and typed transcript of internal SWP lecture (Folder 26)
  - Notes on arrangements for United Secretariat meeting, 1968 May 26 (Folder 27)
  - Notes taken in France, 1968 May-June (Folder 28)
  - Notes on situation in France, 1968 June (Box 55, Folder 1)
  - Speech on Fourth International resolution on Latin America, internal SWP meeting, 1968 December. Outline notes (Folder 2)
  - Notes on China, 1969 (Folder 3)
  - Notes on 9th World Congress of Fourth International, 1969 (Folder 4)
  - "Assessment of the Draft Resolution on Latin America," 1969 February. Mimeograph, and typed Spanish translation (Folder 5)
  - Notes on SWP National Committee plenum, 1969 February 24 (Folder 6)
  - Eulogy for Beatrice Hansen, 1969 March. Notes and typescripts (Folder 7)
  - Report to SWP Political Committee on 9th World Congress of Fourth International, 1969 May 27. Outline notes (Folder 8)
  - Report to SWP New York City branch on 9th World Congress of Fourth International, 1969 June 4. Outline notes (Folder 9)
  - Notes on meeting with Canadian Fourth International leaders, 1969 June 6 (Folder 10)
  - Report to SWP New York City branch, 1969 June 11. Outline notes (Folder 11)
  - Report to SWP Political Committee, 1969 June 11. Outline notes (Folder 12)
  - Report to SWP Political Committee, 1969 July 11. Outline notes (Folder 13)
  - Notes on SWP national convention, 1969 September 5-8 (Folder 14)
  - "Memo on the Iranian Magazine Jahane Nau, " 1969 October 4. Typescript. Authorship uncertain (Folder 15)
  - Notes on United Secretariat meeting, 1969 December (Folder 16)
  - "Summary of Discussions with Carlos (Argentina)," 1969 December. Typescript. Authorship uncertain (Folder 17)
  - Report to SWP Political Committee on upcoming International Executive Committee meeting of Fourth International, 1969 December 3. Outline notes (Folder 18)
  - Notes on meetings of International Executive Committee of Fourth International, 1969 December 23-24 (Folder 19)
  - Notes on Martin Abern, ca. 1970s (Folder 20)
  - Notes on China, ca. 1970s (Folder 21)
  - Notes on Gerry Healy and Workers Revolutionary Party (Great Britain) accusation campaign re assassination of Leon Trotsky, ca. 1970s (Folder 22)
  - Notes on International Socialist Review (1901-1918), ca. 1970s (Folder 23)
  - Notes on Alain Krivine and Pierre Frank, "Again and Always the Question of the International," ca. 1970s (Folder 24)
  - Notes on Latin America, ca. 1970s (Folder 25)
  - Notes, miscellaneous, ca. 1970s (Folder 26)
  - Notes for meeting with Ernest Mandel, 1970 (Folder 27)
  - Notes on International Marxist Group (Great Britain), 1970 (Folder 28)
  - Notes, miscellaneous, 1970 (Folder 29)
  - Notes on Jack Borut, 1970 January (Folder 30)
  - Notes on SWP National Committee plenum, 1970 February 27-March 1 (Folder 31)
  - Speech, 80th birthday of James P. Cannon, 1970 March. Typescript (Folder 32)
  - Speech notes and other notes, United Secretariat meetings, 1970 March 8-9 (Box 56, Folder 1)
  - "A Contribution to the Discussion on Revolutionary Strategy in Latin America," 1970 June 26
    - Typescripts (Folder 2)
    - Notes (Folder 3)
    - Typed Spanish translation (Folder 4)
  - Notes on meeting with Sam Gordon, 1970 July (Folder 5)
  - Speech notes and other notes, United Secretariat meetings, 1970 July 2-5 (Folder 6)
  - Notes, 1970 July 24 (Folder 7)
  - Notes on League for Socialist Action/Ligue Socialiste Ouvriere (Canada) convention, 1970 September 4-7 (Folder 8)
  - Notes on meeting with Ross Dowson, 1970 September 11 (Folder 9)
  - Speech notes and other notes, United Secretariat meeting, 1970 September 19 (Folder 10)
  - Notes on internal SWP meeting re Fourth International, 1970 November 7 (Folder 11)
  - Notes on meetings of International Executive Committee of Fourth International, 1970 December 5-7 (Folder 12)
  - Notes, 1970 December 14 (Folder 13)
  - Speech, Young Socialist Alliance convention, 1970 December 28. Typescript (Folder 14)
  - Notes on Fourth International Japanese section, 1971 (Folder 15)
  - Notes on Latin America, 1971 (Folder 16)
  - Notes, miscellaneous, 1971 (Folder 17)
  - Notes on Hugo Blanco, 1971 January 18 (Folder 18)
  - "Memorandum on Correspondence Relating to London Book Service," 1971 January 20. Typescript (Folder 19)
  - Notes on United Secretariat meetings, 1971 January 23-24 (Folder 20)
  - Report to SWP Political Committee, 1971 March. Outline notes. Includes other notes on meeting (Folder 21)
  - Notes on SWP National Committee plenum, 1971 March 13-16 (Folder 22)
  - "In Defense of the Leninist Strategy of Party Building," 1971 March 19
    - Notes and fragments (Folder 23)
    - Research material (Folder 24-25)
  - Notes, 1971 April (Folder 26)
  - Notes on meeting with Ernest Mandel, 1971 April 16 (Folder 27)
  - Speech notes and other notes, United Secretariat meetings, 1971 April 17-18 (Folder 28)
  - Notes on Richard Garza, 1971 May 8 (Folder 29)
  - Report to SWP Political Committee, 1971 May 11. Outline notes (Folder 30)
  - Speech notes and other notes, United Secretariat meetings, 1971 May 22-23 (Folder 31)
  - Notes, 1971 June 3 (Folder 32)
  - International report to SWP national convention, 1971 August. Outline notes. Includes other notes on convention (Folder 33)
  - Speech notes and other notes, United Secretariat meetings, 1971 September 25-26 (Box 57, Folder 1)
  - Speech notes and other notes, United Secretariat meetings, 1971 October 29-31 (Folder 2)
  - Notes on United Secretariat meetings, 1971 December 21-22 (Folder 3)
  - Draft program of Fourth International, 1972. Notes, holographs and typescripts (Folder 4-5)
  - Notes on The Assassination of Trotsky (motion picture film), 1972 (Folder 6)
  - Notes on Nahuel Moreno and Latin America, 1972 (Folder 7)
  - Notes, miscellaneous, 1972 (Folder 8)
  - "Report on Bolivia and Argentina," 1972. Typescript (Folder 9)
  - Notes on United Secretariat meeting, 1972 February 5 (Folder 10)
  - Speech notes and other notes, United Secretariat meetings, 1972 March 4-5 (Folder 11)
  - Speech notes and other notes, United Secretariat meetings, 1972 April 15-16 (Folder 12)
  - Notes on SWP National Committee plenum, 1972 May 11 (Folder 13)
  - Speech notes and other notes, United Secretariat meetings, 1972 May 29-31 (Folder 14)
  - Notes on Canadian nationalism, 1972 July (Folder 15)
  - Notes on United Secretariat meetings, 1972 September 23-25 (Folder 16)
  - Speech notes and other notes, meetings of International Executive Committee of Fourth International, 1972 December 2-6 (Folder 17)
  - "Statement on Reasons for Postponing Congress [of Fourth International]," 1972 December 6. Typescript (Folder 18)
  - Introduction to Leon Trotsky, The Transitional Program for Socialist Revolution, 1973. Review only (Folder 19)
  - Notes on Bolshevik Tendency, 1973 (Folder 20)
  - Notes on Fourth International, 1973 (Folder 21)
  - Notes on SWP Political Committee meeting, 1973 January 26 (Folder 22)
  - Notes on meeting with committee from Partido Socialista de los Trabajadores (Argentina), 1973 March (Folder 23)
  - Speech notes and other notes, Leninist-Trotskyist Tendency meeting, 1973 March (Folder 24)
  - Speech notes and other notes, United Secretariat meetings, 1973 April 7-8 (Folder 25)
  - Memorandum on United Secretariat intervention in International Marxist Group (Great Britain), 1973 April 8 (with others). Holograph (Folder 26)
  - Notes on League for Socialist Action/Ligue Socialiste Ouvriere (Canada) convention and Central Committee plenum, 1973 April 20-24 (Folder 27)
  - Notes on SWP National Committee plenum, 1973 April 26-29 (Folder 28)
  - Notes, 1973 June 19 (Folder 29)
  - Notes on United Secretariat meeting, 1973 July 10 (Folder 30)
  - Speech notes and other notes, Leninist-Trotskyist Tendency conference, 1973 July 14-15 (Folder 31)
  - Notes on SWP Political Committee meeting, 1973 July 19 (Folder 32)
  - "The Underlying Difference in Methods," 1973 July 24. Typescript (incomplete) (Folder 33)
  - Notes on SWP Political Committee meeting, 1973 July 27 (Folder 34)
  - Speech notes and other notes, SWP national convention, 1973 August 5-9 (Box 58, Folder 1)
  - Speech notes and other notes, Leninist-Trotskyist Faction meetings, 1973 August 13-16 (Folder 2)
  - Draft statement of Leninist-Trotskyist Faction, 1973 September. Outline notes (Folder 3)
  - Notes on United Secretariat meetings, 1973 September 16-19 (Folder 4)
  - Notes on United Secretariat and Parity Commission meetings, 1973 October 23 (Folder 5)
  - Analysis of draft Fourth International political resolution by Ernest Mandel, 1973 November. Notes (Folder 6)
  - Notes on SWP Political Committee meeting, 1973 November 23 (Folder 7)
  - Notes on United Secretariat meetings, 1973 November 27-28 (Folder 8)
  - Notes on United Secretariat meetings, 1973 December (Folder 9)
  - Notes on SWP national convention, 1973 December 26-28 (Folder 10)
  - Marxism vs. Ultraleftism: The Record of Healy's Break with Trotskyism, 1974. Proposed table of contents (Folder 11)
  - Notes on Argentina, 1974 (Folder 12)
  - Notes on Avanzada Socialista (Argentina), 1974 (Folder 13)
  - Notes on Parity Commission meetings, 1974 February 1-2 (Folder 14)
  - Speech notes and other notes, Leninist-Trotskyist Faction meetings, 1974 February 4-5 (Folder 15)
  - Notes on United Secretariat meeting, 1974 February 7 (Folder 16)
  - Speech notes and other notes, 10th World Congress of Fourth International, 1974 February 8-14 (Folder 17)
  - Speech notes and other notes, Leninist-Trotskyist Faction meetings, 1974 February 8-17 (Folder 18)
  - Notes on meeting of International Executive Committee of Fourth International, 1974 February 15 (Folder 19)
  - Notes on United Secretariat meeting, 1974 February 22 (Folder 20)
  - Report to SWP Political Committee on 10th World Congress of Fourth International, 1974 March 8. Outline notes (Folder 21)
  - Report to Leninist-Trotskyist Faction plenum on 10th World Congress of Fourth International, 1974 March 12. Mimeograph (in Spanish) (Folder 22)
  - Notes on United Secretariat meeting, 1974 March 16-17 (Folder 23)
  - Report to Leninist-Trotskyist Faction meeting, 1974 March 19. Outline notes (Folder 24)
  - Message to Duncan Ferguson memorial meeting, 1974 May 3. Notes and typescript (Folder 25)
  - Speech, Intercontinental Press anniversary banquet, New York City, 1974 May 5. Typescript, and announcements (Folder 26)
  - Report to SWP Political Committee on Portugal, 1974 May 24. Notes (Folder 27)
  - Notes on Leninist-Trotskyist Faction meeting, 1974 July 18 (Folder 28)
  - Notes on meeting with Miguel, 1974 August 24 (Folder 29)
  - Speech notes and other notes, Leninist-Trotskyist Faction meetings, 1974 August 25-28 (Folder 30)
  - Discussion with Pierre Lambert and other leaders of United Secretariat and Organisation Communiste Internationaliste (France), 1974 October. Notes and typed transcript (Folder 31)
  - Notes on Leninist-Trotskyist Faction meetings, 1974 October 5-8 (Folder 32)
  - Notes on United Secretariat meetings, 1974 October 12-13 (Folder 33)
  - Notes on United Secretariat meeting, 1974 December 17 (Folder 34)
  - Drafts and notes on Portugal, 1975 (Folder 35)
  - Notes on workers and farmers government, 1975 (Folder 36)
  - Notes, 1975 January 11 (Box 59, Folder 1)
  - Shorthand notes on meetings with Mexican Fourth International leaders, 1975 January 14-29 (Folder 2)
  - Notes on Leninist-Trotskyist Faction meetings, 1975 January 22-31 (Folder 3)
  - Speech notes and other notes, meetings of International Executive Committee of Fourth International, 1975 January 24-29 (Folder 4)
  - Notes on SWP Political Committee meeting, 1975 March (Folder 5)
  - Critique of Ernest Mandel-Livio Maitan-Pierre Frank position on Portugal, 1975 August. Notes (Folder 6)
  - Draft Leninist-Trotskyist Faction resolution on Portugal, 1975 August. Outline notes (Folder 7)
  - Draft statement of Leninist-Trotskyist Faction, 1975 August. Outline notes (Folder 8)
  - "James P. Cannon, the Internationalist," 1975 August. Typescript of speech at Oberlin College (Folder 9)
  - Notes on Portugal, 1975 August 14 (Folder 10)
  - Speech notes and other notes, SWP national convention, 1975 August 16-23 (Folder 11)
  - Notes on Leninist-Trotskyist Faction meeting, 1975 August 24 (Folder 12)
  - "On Healy's 'Investigation': What the Facts Show," 1975 November 14. Printed copy (Folder 13)
  - Speech notes and other notes, United Secretariat meetings, 1975 November 23-24 (Folder 14)
  - Draft statement of Leninist-Trotskyist Faction on internal struggle in Liga Socialista (Mexico), 1976. Typescripts (Folder 15)
  - Editorial notes on Argentina, ca. 1976. Typescripts (Folder 16)
  - "Mexico," 1976 January. Outline notes (Folder 17)
  - Notes on SWP National Committee plenum, 1976 January 2-4 (Folder 18)
  - Report on Liga Socialista (Mexico), internal SWP meeting, 1976 January 22. Outline notes (Folder 19)
  - Speech notes and other notes, United Secretariat meetings, 1976 February 9-15 (Folder 20)
  - Notes on Leninist-Trotskyist Faction meetings, 1976 February 10-16 (Folder 21)
  - Notes on meeting with Lutte Ouvriere (France) leaders, 1976 February 22 (Folder 22)
  - Notes on meeting with Pierre Lambert, 1976 February 24 (Folder 23)
  - Notes on meeting with Mark Jenkins, 1976 February 25 (Folder 24)
  - Notes on meeting with Alan Thornett and colleagues, 1976 February 25 (Folder 25)
  - Notes on meetings with Sam Gordon, 1976 February 25-29 (Folder 26)
  - Notes on meeting with John and Mary Archer, 1976 February 26 (Folder 27)
  - Notes on meeting with Ken Coates, 1976 February 26 (Folder 28)
  - Notes on meeting with Robin Blick and colleagues, 1976 February 27 (Folder 29)
  - Notes on meeting with John Ross, 1976 February 27 (Folder 30)
  - Notes on meeting with Gregor Benton and colleagues, 1976 February 28 (Folder 31)
  - Notes on meeting with Tamara Deutscher, 1976 February 29 (Folder 32)
  - Statement for United Secretariat meeting minutes, 1976 April 9 (with John Barzman). Typescript (Folder 33)
  - Notes on SWP National Committee plenum, 1976 April 29-May 2 (Folder 34)
  - Notes, 1976 May 20 (Folder 35)
  - Deposition, Socialist Workers Party et al. vs. Attorney General of the United States et al., 1976 June 2. Typed transcript (Folder 36-37)
  - Statement for United Secretariat meeting minutes, 1976 June 9 (with Jack Barnes, George Novack and Mary-Alice Waters). Typescript (Folder 38)
  - "Healy Caught in the Logic of the Big Lie," 1976 July 10. Printed copy (Folder 39)
  - Speech, Leninist-Trotskyist Faction meeting, 1976 August. Outline notes (Folder 40)
  - Speech notes and other notes, Leninist-Trotskyist Faction meetings, 1976 August 15-19 (Folder 41)
  - Notes, 1976 October (Folder 42)
  - Notes on Pierre Lambert and Organisation Communiste Internationaliste (France), 1976 October 4-9 (Folder 43)
  - Notes on United Secretariat meetings, 1976 October 14-24 (Folder 44)
  - "Vereeken Begins Learning about Healyism," 1976 December. Printed copy (Folder 45)
  - Notes on Cuba, ca. 1977 (Box 60, Folder 1)
  - Notes, miscellaneous, 1977 (Folder 2)
  - Notes on SWP National Committee plenum, 1977 January 6-9 (Folder 3)
  - Notes on SWP Political Committee meeting, 1977 January 11 (Folder 4)
  - Notes on meeting with Nahuel Moreno, 1977 January 19 (Folder 5)
  - Speech notes and other notes, SWP National Committee plenum, 1977 April 14-17 (Folder 6)
  - "Washington, Moscow, and the Arms Race," The Militant, 1977 June 24. Printed copy (Folder 7)
  - "Two Interpretations of the Cuban Revolution," Socialist Workers Party Discussion Bulletin, 1977 July. Printed copy (Folder 8)
  - Interview by Ben Morris on Freudian psychology, 1977 August. Typed transcript (Folder 9)
  - Notes on Leninist-Trotskyist Faction meetings, 1977 August 15-17 (Folder 10)
  - Notes on United Secretariat meetings, 1977 October 28-November 3 (Folder 11)
  - Notes on Organizacion Socialista de los Trabajadores (Costa Rica) congress and trip to Colombia, and printed transcript (in Spanish) of speech to central committee of Partido Socialista de los Trabajadores (Colombia), 1977 November 27-December 11. See also PHONOTAPE (Folder 12)
  - "Habla Joseph Hansen, Fundador de la IV Internacional," El Socialista (Bogota), 1977 December 17. Printed copy of interview (Folder 13)
  - Memorandum on Intercontinental Press/Inprecor, 1977 December 29. Typescript (Folder 14)
  - Draft reply to Ernest Mandel, 1978. Notes and typescript (Folder 15)
  - Dynamics of the Cuban Revolution: The Trotskyist View, 1978. Typescript of introduction, and reviews (Folder 16)
  - Foreword to Socorro Ramirez, La Campana Socialista, 1978. Typescript (Folder 17)
  - "Healy," 1978. Notes and typescripts (Folder 18)
  - Notes on Colombia, 1978 (Folder 19)
  - Notes on draft resolution of Fourth International, 1978 (Folder 20)
  - Notes, miscellaneous, 1978 (Folder 21)
  - "Reply to Wohlforth," 1978. Holograph and typescript (incomplete) (Folder 22)
  - Notes on United Secretariat meetings, 1978 January 26-29 (Folder 23)
  - Notes on SWP National Committee plenum, 1978 February 24-26 (Folder 24)
  - Notes on United Secretariat meetings, 1978 July 4-6 (Folder 25)
  - "Where Comrade Wohlforth Goes Wrong" (with Dave Frankel), 1978 July 26. Typescript (Folder 26)
  - Notes on SWP expanded Political Committee meeting, 1978 August 14 (Folder 27)
  - Notes on United Secretariat meeting, 1978 August 17 (Folder 28)
  - Notes on SWP National Committee plenum, 1978 December (Folder 29)
  - Eulogy for James Economon, n.d. Notes (Folder 30)
  - "History [of] Farmer-Labor Party," n.d. Notes (Folder 31)
  - "Materialism--Idealism," n.d. Outline notes (Folder 32)
  - Notes on anthropology of Lewis Henry Morgan, n.d. (Folder 33)
  - Notes on French Revolution, n.d. (Folder 34)
  - Notes on Albert Goldman and Felix Morrow, n.d. (Folder 35)
  - Notes on history of Mexico, n.d. (Folder 36)
  - Notes on Paul Lafargue, n.d. (Folder 37)
  - Notes on Harold J. Laski, n.d. (Folder 38)
  - Notes on V. I. Lenin, n.d. (Folder 39)
  - Notes on Ludlow Amendment, n.d. (Folder 40)
  - Notes on Alfred Thayer Mahan, n.d. (Folder 41)
  - Notes on SWP meeting, Chicago, n.d. (Folder 42)
  - Notes on World War I, n.d. (Folder 43)
  - Notes, miscellaneous, n.d. (Folder 44)
  - "Russian Question," n.d. Notes (Folder 45)
  - Shorthand notes, n.d. (Folder 46)
  - Speech on Leon Trotsky, n.d. Outline notes (Folder 47)
- EDITORIAL FILE, 1924-1979.
  Typescripts with handwritten annotations unless otherwise specified
  - Aguinaldo, Emmanuel, "Poland's Contradictions and the Alienations of Its People," 1966 (Box 60, Folder 48)
  - Alexander, David, "Cuba 1967, " 1967 (Folder 49)
  - Andrews, J., et al., "The Roots of the Party Crisis: Its Causes and Solution," 1951. Includes George Clarke, "Some Comments on the 'Contribution to the Discussion, '" 1951. Mimeograph (from Socialist Workers Party Internal Bulletin [1953 April]) with annotations (Folder 50)
  - Archer, Mary and John, "Notes on Healy's Role in Early Days of the British Trotskyist Movement," 1976 (Folder 51)
  - Barnes, Jack, letter to Tim Wohlforth, 1970 (Box 61, Folder 1)
  - Beauvais, Jean-Pierre, "The June Conference of the IMG," n.d. (Folder 2)
  - Blanco, Hugo
    - "The Road of Our Revolution," 1964 (Folder 3)
    - "The Origin of the 'People's Assembly, '" ca. 1971 (Folder 4)
  - Blick, Robin, "How Banda Became an Apologist for the KGB," 1977 (Folder 5)
  - Braverman, Harry, "Korea Truce," 1953 (Folder 6)
  - Camejo, Peter, "After Che, What Next?" 1970 (Folder 7)
  - Cannon, James P.
    - "The New Situation in the Trade Union Movement," 1947 (Folder 8)
    - "Letters to a Historian [Theodore Draper]," 1954-1956 (Folder 9)
    - Speech, Intercontinental Press anniversary banquet, New York City, 1974 (Folder 10)
  - Charlier, Fernand, "Criticism of a Criticism: In Reply to Comrade Nishi," 1970 (Folder 11)
  - Ch'en, Pi-lan
    - "The Thought of Peng Shu-chih and His Position and Activities in the Chinese Communist Party and in the Trotskyist Movement," 1965 (Folder 12)
    - "A Criticism of 'Guerrilla Warfare: The Lessons of China, '" 1971 (Folder 13)
  - Comite de Liaison des Militants Revolutionnaires Portugais (Pour la Reconstruction de la IVe Internationale), statement on Portugal, 1975 (Folder 14)
  - Couturier, L.
    - "What I Saw in Algiers in August," ca. 1962 (Folder 15)
    - "UNIR and Us," 1966 (Folder 16)
  - Cowley, Joyce, et al., "In Defense of a Revolutionary Perspective: A Statement of Basic Position," 1962. Mimeograph with handwritten annotations (Folder 17)
  - Dobbs, Farrell, election campaign telecast address as Socialist Workers Party candidate for president of the United States, 1960 (Folder 18)
  - "The Downfall of Mossadegh," 1953 (Folder 19)
  - Dowson, Ross
    - "Algiers Conference," ca. 1963 (Folder 20)
    - Article on Canadian Trotskyism, 1971 (Folder 21)
  - Edwards, Theodore, "The UN," 1958 (Folder 22)
  - Fidler, Richard, article on Quebec, 1967 (Folder 23)
  - Fion, Rudi, article on Guatemala, 1969 (Folder 24)
  - Fourth International. International Committee
    - "Fourth Congress of the International Committee of the F.I. Being Prepared," ca. 1970 (Folder 25)
    - Security and the Fourth International, 1975 (Folder 26)
  - Fourth International. International Executive Committee
    - "A la Defense de la IVe Internationale!" 1953. Mimeograph with handwritten annotations (Folder 27)
    - Statement on Liga Socialista (Mexico), 1976 (Folder 28)
  - Fourth International. International Secretariat
    - "The Rise and Fall of Stalinism," 1953. Mimeograph with handwritten annotations (Folder 29)
    - "Crisis of Leadership in the Soviet Bureaucracy," 1955 (Folder 30)
  - Fourth International. United Secretariat
    - "Proposed Statutes of the Fourth International," 1965 (Folder 31)